Laura Andrea Mujica

Visual Designer

Córdoba, AR · +54-9-351-2481479 · hola@laumujica.com.ar · linkedin.com/in/lauraamujica · behance.net/lauraamujica

As a curious, self-taught individual, I am recognized for my quick thinking and abundance of ideas. Throughout my +10 years of experience in graphic design, I enhanced my skills and developed methodologies that streamlined project development from start to finish. My focus is always on understanding and meeting human needs and desires. I particularly enjoy working with typography and color matching, and I take great pride in my ability to meticulously search for and eliminate design imperfections to ensure the highest level of quality in the final product.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graphic Design Teacher

August 2019 - October 2022

Independent, Córdoba, AR

- Trained +30 students on design software such as Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, and Corel Draw.
- Instructed students about design principles and reduced their skill insecurities by at least 75%.
- Developed assignments and projects that engaged students, resulting in a 70% increase in their commitment.
- · Coached small business owner students to design faster and save at least 3 hours per project.
- Mentored students to exceed course objectives, achieving a 100% completion rate for every course.

Freelance Visual Designer

August 2019 - November 2019

Technosur, Córdoba, AR

- · Designed visuals that represented the organization or client's needs, resulting in a 75% increase in their visibility.
- Developed +15 logos, business cards, and websites for clients (using Google Sites + personal domain).
- Wrote 360° proposals and estimates for design projects and negotiated contracts with clients, achieving a 100% acceptance rate for offers.
- Collaborated with other designers, copywriters, and vendors and expanded my network by 80%.

Jr. Graphic Designer

August 2018 - March 2019

Oferta Gráfica, Córdoba, AR

- · Prepared and organized original files for 3 different types of printing systems: offset, digital, and solvent printing.
- Supported for pre- and post-production of plotter printing and reduced production time by 20 hours per week.
- · Led the creation of graphic design of internal pieces for the company, reducing the responsibilities of seniors by 50%.
- Processed +120 orders through the online platform & Mercado Libre, ensuring timely delivery and customer satisfaction.

Freelance Graphic Designer

February 2011 - February 2018

Ideas Nómade, Córdoba, AR

- Created +100 logos and minimal visual identity for small entrepreneurs and businesses through research, interviews, and in-person meetings.
- Designed, printed, serially produced, and bound annual agendas over a +3 year period.
- Gained +200 clients by innovating handmade binding products and processes in Córdoba city.
- Directed photography at events with professional equipment for 2 years, including photo editing and retouching and creation of photo books.

EDUCATION

Associate Degree in Advertising

Colegio Universitario IES, Córdoba, AR — February 2007 – November 2011

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

UX/UI Design

Coderhouse – August 2022 – November 2022

Web Development

Coderhouse – August 2022 – November 2022

Manual QA Testing

Coderhouse - July 2022 - August 2022

Design Thinking

Scrum México – June 2022 – July 2022

LANGUAJES

English: C2 Proficient (EF SET Certificate)

TOOLS & SKILLS

Adobe Creative Studio, Figma, HTML & CSS, Optimal Workshop, UX/UI, Usability Research, Wireframing & Prototyping, Mockup, Journey Map, Visual Design, Storyboards, Branding, Web Design, User Interface Design, Design Systems, Innovation, Empathy, Design Thinking